Yeah, so you can probably see it.
I think I went on a bit too much about here.
Probably went off track here.
Let's have a look.
So the question was, what?
The question was, what's the most appropriate way to trade midflow, was it?
The most appropriate way to trade counterflow during midflow.
Midflow, yeah.
So what basically means if prices go in in a certain direction, how do you fade it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
if it's moving in a way
which is quite strong
midflow
are the visual characteristics
of one-sided strength
every single move to it
so any move that moves in a specific direction
if you look inside of it
it will always have mid-flow
because price is fractured
the price is the formation
of the liquidity dynamics
so the liquidity dynamics have to exist
before the prices are created
there already has to be
sell weakness by liquidity
strength and then there has to be a market
order that comes in that pushes
price to the weaker side
well before the candles formed
yeah yeah right
so the state of liquidity
governs price movement
and then the eventual price
action that we see is a direct reflection
of the state of liquidity
that would then imply
that each environment
reflects the state of liquidity
so price goes up
it reflects a lack of sell liquidity and more market for order buyers.
Not more market order ratio than one and vice versa.
It moves down.
And what we've seen is that market order buying doesn't just come in relentlessly and infinitely.
It dries off because of variable volume flow.
The tempo at which volume comes in, it's always ebbin and flowing.
So in a move with this directional strength, where there's heavy liquidity on one side relative to the other side.
relative to the other side
compared to the other side
and variable volume flow
we see midflow characteristics
now I'm telling you then
if you're trying to trade against the flow
you're essentially trading on the weaker side
of the market now
yeah yeah you are
so this is where the question was
the visual characteristics
are quite simple
I can't draw out
right these are the visual characteristics
price runs out
draws back in
runs out the high doesn't hold
price gaps past it
and then draws back in.
So as a result of deal
behaviour, you can trade,
you can counterflow,
most appropriately this way.
For example,
bullish mid-flow,
there will be highs
that have dried off
due to dealer receiving information.
No, like this,
the high doesn't dry off
because the dealer receives information.
No, no, no.
This is, it's a bit jumbled up.
If you read on.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's important that you understand
the dealer reacting to information.
They're going to do it anyway.
Just a matter of if price
is going up,
down, left,
right they have access to information about the strength the volume the weakness that we don't
because they get all the volume on all the flow based off that they can make much more informed
decisions about where prices is likely to go and manage their risk that way they don't necessarily
have to speculate that cable's going to go up because it's bullish they can see the weakness on
the cell side they can see that volume's coming in they can actually see when other liquidity
providers are updated their quotes yeah each quote is updated up to a million times in a
second within the first few hundred thousand changes the dealers uh the automated systems at least
they can start to predict which way the price is going to lead next so there's the start of the
second here's the share so here's the start of the second here's the final millionth update
this takes a second around the first few 200 300 000 updates they can with highly
degree of accuracy, start to respond and anticipate, because of the patterns and the series of
price updates here, they're going to anticipate where prices are going to go next. That's just
the piece of information they have access to. Not only that, they have access to volume or the
flow, they can tell how much volume is coming in compared to the available liquidity they have
in-house, et cetera, et cetera. So they're always looking at each of us quotes. They're always
looking on all the channels that they update their prices on. So they might be, they might be
update in their prices or sending prices
to one client. They might
have another client on a different venue, a third-point
Jaguarian. They might have another client, or
they might be sending prices to an ECN.
So they're managing many, many
different channels of liquidity that
they send out to the market.
Yeah, all the ones. And
they can basically assess each of them
simultaneously, make sure the price
invested appropriately at the right time,
et cetera, et cetera. So
the highs do not dry off because
a dealer receiving information, the market goes into an environment where price runs out as a result
of weak equity and volume chasing after it. Okay. Right. So prices and bullish mid-flow,
it runs out to the upside here because there's a lack of sell liquidity there. And when that
volume order shot comes in, the market order by, it's much more likely to push it out because
there's already weakness in the sell liquidity. Deals then don't take on short positions. They run away
from providing sell liquidity, the whole market goes into a state of inefficiency.
It's not trade.
The market isn't trading well.
The buyers can't find sell liquidity.
There's hardly any present there.
All right.
So the price dries off as a result of two reasons.
A lack of sell liquidity, which is then compounded and pronounced made worse by
deal of behavior, like you said here.
Right?
Yeah.
And number two, number two, sorry, the second, the second point.
away from that, price is also drying off because the volume is unrealistic to expect it to come in
forever and ever and ever at the same side. If somebody went 30 million long here, it doesn't mean
somebody else is buying 30 million, somebody else buying 30 million and 100 million there, 500 million
there and 100 million there, and they continue to buy it up super aggressively at more and more
expensive prices without drying off. It's ridiculous. So price dries off because of variable volume
flow and that move out is weak because of dealer behavior and a compound effect of
sell equity chasing away dealers avoiding adverse selection it's important that you can
differentiate even the subtle differences between what i'm saying this makes absolutely no sense
okay i think i probably worded it wrong it's it's a bit jumbled up there yeah um there's no
space for wording you up wrong you know because this makes no sense so there's no space to get
wrong basically. Okay. Yeah, yeah, that's quite.
I can't write that. As it like,
you can't be wrong. I'm not saying you can't
be wrong. I'm saying this is unacceptable
to leave it as this, even though
it's totally wrong.
I tell you, I tell you what it
means. It's your own, the
on this is on you to make sure you understand it.
If you don't understand, so you go away, you start
thinking about what I'm talking about here.
What, you know, what's the difference between
writing dealer receiving information and dealer
behavior here? Yeah. Also,
it's not a totally accurate answer because
There's variable volume flow as well that applies here.
How far the price run moves out is more related to the deemed behavior.
But price drying off is related to variable volume flow.
Okay.
That makes more sense now.
So, yeah, we have to be entirely accurate about this because the foundation is your understanding.
Based off the understanding, you then go and observe price behaviors and it all returns
to the foundation.
So, yeah, that's cool.
It's already done sell equity in the first place.
The dealer starts moving sell equity from the market.
the dealer avoids providing cell
okay avoids
yeah
avoid taking on short positions
in effect
sell liquidity is
drawn away from price
that is the effect of it
but by removing
sell liquidity
imagine I had a sell limit order here
they can't remove that sell limit order
yeah that's true
right so they can't necessarily remove it
but they can avoid from
avoid providing it
and they can take on the opposite side
of my sell liquidity
so they can go longer against me
that's fine my order has been filled
but this sell liquidity was not given
to the market or the buyer that was trying to
find it yeah
they can control the distribution of liquidity
they can avoid taking on short positions
which has an effect of
sell liquidity drawing away from volume
but not necessarily remove it
it's probably not entirely accurate
protective mechanism following of the dealers
cool as this happens price moves and efficiently
and then if they price drives off
you to not off.
Not due to him
fix illiquity in the middle of a run
but just due to exhaustion.
Okay, cool, that's good.
So here what you're describing is
why.
I actually
I understand what you're trying to say,
but here you're discussing with
you're trying to explain
why price dries off.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
why price falls off in mid-floor, yeah.
Even though there's bullish strength
or there's bi-liquity
and there's bullishness in the market.
Why is it drying up up here if buyers are strong?
no why is it selling etc no that makes sense um prices thinly dispersed again doesn't make any
sense at all prices thinly dispersed it's not the liquidity left behind is thinly dispersed oh yeah yeah
yeah that's a dumb mistake right so liquidity left behind and i make uh just to avoid confusion
you should type you should write also what side of liquidity as well is it sell liquidity that's
didn't you disperse left behind?
No, no, bi-liquidity
is the loss-spersed.
Actually, the bi-liquity
remains back down at call,
typically, right?
Or back of the inventory,
sorry, back of the inventory.
So the most appropriate
words trade mid-flows after, yeah, that's exactly
right. You can trade about
push a price back into range.
Well, again, I wish
we could push price around. We can't.
This tends to happen
as a result of the conditions being created
as a result of the order flow dynamics
so weakness on the south side
order flow response
that liquidity draws away price chases after it
it leaves behind thinness
the volume dries off because it's not unlimited
and then it takes any light selling
to push price right like that
these conditions are being created
as a result of the microstructure
the EU behaviour
so the price draws back into the range
highly consistently
is much much more likely to draw back
to range than it is to continue forever and ever and ever
and ever. Yeah, yeah.
So the key characteristic of midflow, price holding by a basis in this case.
Yeah, so the characteristic of midflow is price holding bases in the direction of the strength
and the opposing cell, embellishment flow, at least, the opposing apexes, the fractal
highs, they're not holding.
Yeah, the weaker, yeah.
So the last base here is holding, right?
The last base holds, the last base holds, but consistently the apex don't hold.
It's like higher highs and higher.
okay um and as liquid where am i so key cut yeah as liquidity maintains itself at the last inventory
yeah in stable balance midflow and my own liquidity chase and more aggressive yeah right so the answer
this to my second part of the question which type of midflow is more favourable to counterflow
and it would be in the one where it's not the liquidity is less aggressive yeah yeah the more stable
in accepting higher prices the price will pop out draw back into that base at least at least
or highly consistently you know at least would imply it's like guaranteed yeah um so yeah
thin and you're not talking to me probably right an explanation so i'm just going to be a dick
about that one so yeah thin extensions past ties training got point of exhaustion and
countering price here at least because the last five days and bullish day we need countering price
here at least to the back now sorry i'm fucking dyslexic it can probably sound back but i'm not
all right cool yeah it's right you know what you're talking about yeah just got to just sort out some
words in there because it's not entirely accurate or could probably yeah yeah that and that
makes no sense um what's it going to say so it's important that you realize that the price
formation is occurring after the state of liquidity existed so they say liquidity proceeds it
price is a function of it that we can draw a principle away from that price is a function of
state of liquidity.
Okay. Yeah.
All right. Or probably more accurate is price of function of liquidity dynamics.
Because the liquidity doesn't stay in one place. It's changing dynamically, you know.
So that's that. Another very, very critical principle here is price actually reflects the state
of liquidity then. So PRSOM. Price reflects state of liquidity. In other words, you know,
price is embellished mid-flow. What state of liquidity is that, is that, is that?
that reflecting? Well, mid-thickness, weak offers. Yeah. If prices aggressively popping to the upside,
that's also an even more pronounced, more, you know, there's a greater imbalance in this example,
but they both reflect a lack of sell liquidity and aggressive market orders pushing price here,
right? So any directional move has to have that. There has to be greater market limit order ratio,
market order ratio
versus the limit orders
if price is relatively stable
you know
there they can be entirely weak liquidity
on both sides of that range
there just isn't enough market order buying
or market order selling at the same time
to push price up or down
so it's typically a low volume state
we sometimes call that a low liquidity state
it's probably more accurate to call it low volume state
okay right
most ranges are low liquidity
states, low-volume states.
Now, what do you think happens?
Right, but I'm thirsty, shit.
What do you think happens in this relatively stable condition?
Is it favourable for dealers to provide, like, take on short and long positions here?
When clients try to go long and short, you think dealers like a stable condition?
Yeah, dealers do like stable conditions, yeah.
Yeah, they can continue to spread.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, they'll probably hold on to this for a while longer as well.
until there's a tiny bit of weakness here and the right volume comes in right they will then suddenly the price you know the price thing engines will kick off will suddenly avoid taking short positions now typically what you see is the longer prices in low liquidity states the bigger than move out of it okay why is that so I'm mainly talking about high time from low liquidity states where
volume that comes in
so if price ever goes into a higher
type of lowly state like cable
this for the last four weeks over then
the last two three days
it's typically because
of some event or some
uncertainty in the market where the market does not
not know what direction to take
so there's a lack of willingness to take on
directional bets
so we've had this Brexit discussion
and uncertainty around where these Brexit talks will go
whether it'll be a hard deal or no deal
or a hard exit, et cetera, et cetera,
or whether we'll get some resolution
and we'll continue to discuss,
you know, we'll come and work out things.
Because of that, we've seen cable
just maintain this relatively consistent,
low volume state.
Inside of it, we've had major prices.
We've had up, down, down, up,
and we've had major, major moves,
but it's consistently failed to move out directionally.
So whilst that's happening,
all the liquidity is building up inside of there.
There's sell liquidity in there,
there's bi liquidity in there,
there's sell liquidity and some in the middle of you right so there's trading happening here
yeah as soon as price pushes out or around the low liquidity state there's a lack of willingness
to trade the uncertainty's present inside of it so inside of it low volume it's not pushing price
in any direction immediately around it as a result or a function of the uncertainty there's a lack
of liquidity there kind of draws away from price okay you get it so there was sell limit orders here
those bi-libert orders here, it draws away from price.
Now, when that volume comes out and price finally starts to push out, the initial volatility
further compounds, the lack of willingness to go short, and sell liquidity draws further away.
So any buying, once it started to push through the range at the right time, there was a bit of weakness
there, it kicked off that price-shifting mechanism.
It will have to continue running deeper in the box to find sell liquidity.
and at a time of uncertainty as well
I can probably imagine
yeah
whenever you have these
that kind of macro
or political events
there will be
like the move we had out on
Monday was it
I think Tuesday
it was a type of move
you know I'll just quickly show you
okay
cool I can see it
right so
on a fractal basis
yeah
we've had multiple low volume
states shoot out as price starts running out whatever sell equity here is literally dispersing
it's not wanting to take on short position i'm not saying there's no sell equity there there is
the price would have stopped you know if we look inside of here what you'll see is bullish midflaw
so what you'll see it wasn't just a straight shot to the upside it was some areas where some
cell equity was present volume dried off price actually stabilizes multiple times throughout that
period look stabilizes their low volume some sell liquidity properly
proper thick by liquidity there
and some trade is being facilitated.
Right, price pops out again
and the same thing repeats over and over again
until we broke midflow quite distinctively,
I guess here, popped out
and we saw that huge move back in.
This was sometime last week.
Yeah, if not last week, the week before.
This is last Monday, actually.
That's not the point. The point I'm saying is
after low volume stays,
as price starts to get some volume
and one direction opens up as a result of
dealers avoiding taking on that side of the market
where there's a compound effect
the more volatility that comes in
the less willingness there is to provide
some liquidity and the dynamic repeats
so the further price runs
at least initially at any way
at least initially out of the range the further price is running
is already a lack of liquidity there
price continues to run and that liquidity doesn't turn up
until a major levels
it typically hits like a distinct level
which you actually didn't in that case
I'll be honest with you
it typically will hit a distinct level
and then start to draw back in
okay this is why I had this line drawn on
for two weeks
because it didn't hit a distinct level
I kind of expected it
to kind of push past it
finally to this decent level here
it looks like it reacted perfectly off that
yesterday yeah
anyway
so yeah the longer price
and low liquidity states
especially on something like this
price
round up for like multiple days here as soon as that volume started to come in this this
side just evaporated there was a hard-dainte's a liquidity there was some but there wasn't
enough and by volume obviously there was definite large buy-end going on price three right back
come into this distinct area we see that that happens on a repeated basis on any time frame
it's more pronounced on the higher time frame so here you had a low liquidity state volume short price
pops out and then it reaches back into the opposing so liquidity and then response now if you look at
this if we look at this on the weekly this would be a huge low liquidity state and price
because he pretty big move out we had this low liquidity state preceding boris jonson's election
huge pump out here we start to see coronavirus like news kind of kick off and then we had the
the effect you know the breakout essentially we
have this is going to continue in my opinion
this low liquidity state what happened to hear
I don't think there was anything behind this
any sense from at least
oh there was a global wave of
taking this
the US dollar was selling off
money was piling into Europe
and risk assets like S&P 500
Dow Jones etc
we just saw a risk on wave which is quite
unusual but we saw that happen
again this was
two three days
or a week or two leading up to
their deadline
for Brexit negotiations approaching
I think the weekend before
the deadline they came out here and said
they're going to negotiate and they're going to sit down the table
exactly the same thing as happened here
it happened here and price popped
out and then Boris Johnson's election
and this is again a smaller low-liquity
state that one day before
Boris Johnson's election
result
we have interest rate
decision here two days before
it this is a Friday and yeah that's a Friday I think we had the interest rate decision before
or we had a US interest rate decision there and price popped out obviously I can't remember
every single day but it happens quite I'm surprised you know this many to be honest with you
yeah so yeah low volume state pop out the longer the lower volume state this is a really
good one price surges or something like that that's cool if you go through if you go through
The intro PDF, let me just pull that out quickly.
I just want to quickly stream through it, and then go one.
Which PDF did you say?
The intro one.
I forget, honestly, I forget this name, bro.
I can you quickly find it.
I think it's intro at the prize swing or some politics like that.
Maybe so long ago.
All right, yeah, that.
Can you see it?
Yeah.
So these are like being, like, this is where I initially started to
introduce you to the liquidity principles that we've been looking at.
you already know this
you already know that
right
we're kind of looking at the dynamics behind
why the price swings occur
not going to go through at all
because you already know it
this is critical
volatility is a function available
liquidity
but that means is price only runs out
that aggressively
not necessarily because it's strong
buying but typically because it's just
a weakness in sell liquidity
yeah
the same way
if you're selling something here
and you're selling two of them
and then somebody's selling something here,
one of them, if I go market order three,
price quickly jumps there.
Right?
The volatility is massive
as a result of price accelerating
to find equity.
There's a lack of liquidity
the volatility is a function of available liquidity
and there's a lack of liquidity
volatility is higher.
It's important though you understand
that liquidity is passive
so if limit orders, it's not
constant it's not constantly the same so as you can see there's two here there's nothing nothing
nothing and then there's one there it's not like this one one one yeah yeah price goes to the
weak less liquid side you know that because this price can move against the sentiment and trend so here
you see the price goes up down up down up down it went down up down up down up down up down up down
up down up down up then in that day sentiment so the mass character you know the mass attitude
attitude of the market and traders or investors and anyone who invests or who has volume
in the FX market did they change their mind about the underlying strength of the economy
the direction of the pound versus the US dollar 10 15 times a single day and over the period
of nine days here or 11 whatever the number is no effects again like we said isn't dominated
by speculators who who trade in the market to buy a low and sell high yeah it's
not dominated by them. You have liquidity and the sources of liquidity coming from a very, very wide, you know, pool. There's different types of participants. They all have different purposes. They all come to the same market. And all that liquidity and volume comes into, you know, and makes up these prices. So on any given day, this is actually, you can see this huge move, right? This is actually on 2018 bearish trend in the latter part of the year. Or 2019, sorry.
so cable sold off almost all year last year over there after september but we still saw huge moves to the upside and then on our smaller bases as well we're seeing a general bearish midflow here for a matter of days but we still saw multiple moves back up because the volume isn't a constant price goes to a less liquid side and these moves here so there's a relative area of stability weak by liquidity module the shot price rooms out really inefficiently once that volume dries off it's left
behind a whole barren
fucking area
of liquidity
there's the hard ending
in the way
and light
buying is able
to push by itself
so multiple
things happen
there
there's
thicker
liquidity
sell liquidity
there
there's
relatively thick
buy liquidity
there
in the middle
there was
strong cell
volume
but no liquidity
the volume
dried off
right
so even in
this small
area of prices
there's so many
changes
there's
thick liquidity
up there
then liquidity
in the middle
there's
low volume
there
the volume shop pushes price out there's high volume wanting to trade in a move down but not being able
it's not matching with buy equity because it's hardly any day you get it yeah so the point in
making is the market's so dynamic in that sense every single price move is unique and individual
in that sense and we see price movement more as a function of liquidity than we do strong
directional or moves with intent there's not a big big buyer pushing price up there
there's not a big big buyer pushing price up here arguably for the whole two day period or
one two three days there's hardly any big buyers are sellers in this market there is no directional
intent here um price is just there's weak buy liquidity left in this move up relatively light
selling is pushing price down yeah right and it's a more low volume state here after that
initial move up, right? So the volume intensity is always changing. That's a very big volume
flow. Price goes to less liquid side. As a result of the auto flow dynamics created these
small conditions where the microvolatility, basically, the price runs out, it leads behind
thinness, it's running out for certain reasons. That's happening much more frequently than
there is a huge seller pushing price down, pushing in a directional trend aggressively all day
every day that shift was not happening so in my opinion trend trading is uh it's just a
ridiculous idea and fx there's certain pairs that trend that you're wrong and you can be a trend
trader just in something that's really really liquid you won't get major trends
or typically you won't get major trends uh so this is a critical thing to understand
it doesn't matter what the direction is you know price and bullish mid-flow why is it drying
on because it's moving to a less liquid side due to that you know that is a move against
the broader strength in the market we can take advantage of it we don't necessarily have to
trade with the trend at all times so yeah volume and sentiment is not a constant price
chopped around over the course of an ad trading days did sentiment change no this sentiment
remained bearish throughout that whole period it was July 2019 however the selling was
not a constant. It was just consistent. It was consistently strong
sell equity there and ended up, as you can see. It had this range
price came down, drew back up to the core, basically, their origin
and sell equity accepted lower prices here. And we
sold the, it came slightly more aggressive, but it wasn't constantly
selling, yeah, and it hardly ever does. Yeah. It's critical
that we realize that the volume will dry off rather than continue most of the time
selling
cell volume was
not constantly pushing
the lower and pound
rather it continued
to nudge, nudge, nudge, nudge, nudge,
nudge, nudge, nudge,
rather than relentless selling.
That's what is, you know,
again, facilitate in these conditions
volume, not constant, which is the same
thing as saying variable volume,
yeah, right?
Volatility is a function of available
liquidity if there's an area of weakness,
a.k.a. void
of offers, aka
sell liquidity, above
price, and the bids are relatively
thick, even just
slightly thicker, price well
moved through that weak area.
As soon as volume comes to it.
And the same implies
for the opposite side with this thicker sell liquidity
and weaker by liquidity, price will
move down as volume comes to it.
Understanding this on a conceptual level
so you can conceptualize what's
going on behind the price moving in your mind
it's the next level of understanding
for why prices are the way they are.
You know, price action
is just much more deeper
than the candle stick.
We know it's dynamic.
We know it's changing tempo all the time
from slow to fast.
It's consistently moving direction.
We went up, then down, then up, then down.
There's fractal price swings,
there's large price swings.
There's, you know, again,
tempo is changing all the time.
All of this is a result of the liquidity state
or the liquidity dynamics.
Same thing.
I'm not understanding what's happening on, you know, behind that, so you can visualize, you know, what price is doing or what's occurring in the market behind the price formation.
It is getting the next level of understanding.
Seeing price through that prism of liquidity seeking, so volume seeks liquidity, liquidity and the characteristics of dealing.
It's extremely important if you want to take advantage of, first of all, the characteristic of the market, which in effect is the liquidity on both sides.
That means you can go, we can be buyers and sellers.
you can expect sell liquidity to turn up we can expect buy liquidity to turn up quite
consistently and reliably that's a FX characteristic and and everything else as well
so if you want to trade the like the nature of prices because running further than
this short so it creates the bigger dislocation the price is disdicated
is a great capacity of price to push it back into range back to a level of stability
yeah if you want to take advantage of these behaviors first you have to know
why they exist, what's facilitating them, and this is that was the discussion. It's really
appropriate, by the way, that we discussed this. It feeds directly into what you just
learned about mid-flow. So had that to run, you have to remember, volume is in a constant. It's
changing at the end of the day, start of the day, during the day, for net business, it's
emin and flowing, right? Almost endlessly, price goes into a low volume, stable area of trading,
So price stabilizes and then pops
It stabilizes and pops
All the time
Bolly's changing
And you already know what this is
Right
I'm here implying that there's a
Six million sell liquidity there
Six million there six million there six million there six million there
Six million there six six six yeah
This implies that there is consistent liquidity at every price level
In reality we know it's not true
There could be no liquidity here
There could be 60 million there
1.6 million there
there can be different sizes
and they're not linearly distributed
but this is just a hypothetical example
where I illustrate that you can have
the same amount of sell liquidity here
at every level
10 gets filled you know 6 gets filled
10 etc etc
until this has now completely
been filled and price starts
drawing back down
even though there was still the same amount
of sell liquidity at every price level
you get it
Yeah.
What's pushing price down here?
Is it the self-strength or the bi-reakness then?
The bi-weakness.
Yeah, because we have the same self-strength line,
every single fucking level.
Yeah.
So here's what we discussed.
Today, liquidity draws away from around the low-volume state,
especially as price starts off and draw out of it.
So any volume, as soon as it pushes through,
it finds a barren fucking area of hardly any liquidity there,
and it increases the volatility,
or the volatility increases as the volume
tries to find the liquidity sitting somewhere in the book.
It's important, again, to realize that it's no,
it's not like it's completely illiquid.
There is liquidity there, just not in huge amounts.
So here, this green line shows a trade I was in.
It's one of those things that it just shows with the trade history.
I was long from somewhere earlier.
An event happened.
I had my take profit at the price would have spent less than a second here, by the way.
It's five tick shop.
it literally would have gone up
and then right back off
this high somewhere down to here
I had my son limit
which is a take profit in a buy order here
price just literally went there
to find my cell limit right
this was a surge
out of this low volume low liquidity state
volume came in
cell liquidity just was vanished basically
there was none of it there
in this instance there was just nothing here
literally nothing
it jumped 35 tips with an amount
literally progress in second and then I had my cell limit order at a level on the left.
Now the point I'm raising here is, why was my cell limit order there?
Right?
I put it in an area where I deemed it to be sell liquidity.
So I don't expect price to get past that level.
Regardless if it if it draws up into there or if it shoots up into there,
this is the level I deemed with a sell liquidity.
That ties kind of back in with price reflecting state of liquidity.
Over time, we will be able to see
consistencies and price behavior
where there is liquidity, where it concentrates.
And it's typically back at origins.
Like you have an origin of move down,
an origin of the move up,
price responds at these origins.
And it runs through the middle.
So here you have a fractal price run down
and a fractured price run up.
In the middle of these price rooms,
it's a thinly traded box.
And that should have been just inaki there.
The middle of the trade, thinly traded, and it's typically the least responsive.
So you can see price does respond, but it doesn't reverse.
It does respond, it doesn't reverse.
Right?
And we typically get huge, huge, and the successful reversals of the origin slash core areas.
Yeah, so it seems that like the middle levels, you can still trade off them, but in this...
I do trade off them.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I mean, like, in here...
But...
Yeah, this area, you wouldn't really expect the middle area to push it to new lows.
And price has already embellished midflow here, yeah?
Yeah.
So it's quite, it's weak midflow.
I guess, yeah, that did push the new highs.
It looks like the price worked midflow.
Yeah, so it is weak midflow.
But as we know in midflow, the highs do not hold.
The buy bases continue to hold.
I guess the last inventory here held and price pushed down.
So if that's the case, abolished midflow,
we see price run out, get super, super weak, and dry off.
It doesn't have to hit strong sell liquidity as it draws back into range.
It builds up again and repeats.
The reason these highs aren't holding, as we discussed last session,
if there was already 10 million, aka weak liquidity there,
this tested it, grabbed four of it.
There's now less sell liquidity left here.
This weak area has become even weaker and then prices and it continues to stream through it.
So I will use residual levels,
which is the middle of a price room
the class has residual
just left over liquidity
there's relatively thin
liquidity left over there
but I would only trade
under them in specific conditions
and my trade duration will be specifically
short as well
so I will only look to take the trade
of this weak area if they move into it
is weak
and the red flow is relatively stable
and my trade duration won't be where I'm
expecting a reverse line
I don't care if that happens
I do not care if price ends up reversing off this midflow level
probably over time that is a less likely scenario
for example it's like having a 80, 20% chance
80% not likely to break down
it's unlikely to sell off at this last range
until the big box price run
until the big midflow shows weakness
and it hits a good level on the left
it's unlikely to happen
I do not care about the times it does that there
I'm not going to take these short positions
trying to look for that scenario
which is less probable
it's left like
Yeah, no there's no point of it
In each individual
You know
Each individual time
It may sell off
Right
Just like if you played Russian roulette
You have a one in six chance of dying
You could
You could fucking miss that bullet
Time and time and time again
But there's always that one chance
You get now
Your head get licked off
right
the same thing
kind of applies here
there's a less
likelihood
lower chance of price
breaking through
the last inventory
is possible
a dozen
etc
we're trading with
the flow
all right
when I traded
with the flow
normally I trade
against it
yeah
I'm an exhaustion
trader
I trade the exhaustion
I'm sure
about
ox sake
I trade the exhaustion
I don't trade
the strength
usually
this is trading
with the strength
here I traded
with this show
I show my entry
and whatnot
so you can watch that
it's pretty
this in February this year
which one is this in
so lesson trade examples
you should have access to it
yeah yeah
I do have that
and then
I guess
you might
you might benefit
from this one
is like a 15 minute
video
oh fuck you know
it's 45 minutes
so
it's still a call like a
local
They might help you.
I don't remember this.
You've done so many.
I don't...
I'm not surprised if you don't remember them.
Yeah.
I remember you took some WTI shorts,
like literally to the actual...
To the PIP, man.
Look, it's a case of the behaviour is consistent.
I know the parameters and the conditions
leaning up to the behaviours
so I can recognise them in real time.
And take the chance, bro.
That's it.
Just take the chance.
Some entries.
we're just so mad
that I was just thinking
like how
yes using these price swing
stages so we have midflow
I know what to look for after midflow
I want the break of midflow
and then I want that surge
and usually this last surge
has its own fractal search
right and then I'm using
the fractal nature of price
combined with the location of this price
swing what's location
it's in the parabolic phase
the location here is midflow
the location here is the breaker midflow sideways stage
is the parabolic phase
I'm looking to trade after the sideways pop
in good areas of opposing liquidity
and my timing is kind of
here I'm being quite aggressive
so you know why are these conditions occurring
we've seen them happen over and over again in price
we know what midflow reflects
this then starts to reflect the weakness
in the tempo and rhythm and then this
is just a phenomenon that's present
in the way volume and liquidity
is delivered into the market.
It happens all the time.
I can't tell you why,
though.
The only explanation I have for it is
whatever inventory are available by
the willingness to buy here,
whatever inventory is present,
at least a large percentage of it
tries to get filled aggressively.
Okay.
So here we're seeing quite a nice tempo and rhythm.
And then that first sign of weakness
as price pushes down,
the liquidity aggressively snaps up
and it starts to get delivered into the market
because the purpose of that execution algorithm
is to fill the volume and liquidity
and it may be some kind of parameters
built into these execution algos
which turn into aggressive mode
when a certain level of volatility is here
or certain corrections happened to avoid
basically to make sure they complete their task
but this is just a phenomenon that's present
at that highs and lows